# **Belal Kourkmas**

syte1.github.io/

Email: BelalKourkmas@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/belalk GitHub: github.com/Syte1

#### Bio

Software developer with 3 years of professional experience, and 4 years of educational experience.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Python, Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, C, C++, SQL, HTML, CSS, Kotlin

Frameworks/Technologies: React, Redux, Django, Flask, Node, Express, Tailwind CSS, Docker, Git, AWS, Linux

**Technical Skills**: OOP Design, REST APIs, Microservices, Containers, Databases, Unit testing, CI/CD, Version-Control, UI/UX **Other Skills**: Native English Speaker, Problem-solver, Detail-oriented, Creative, Team-player, Cooperative, Self-disciplined

#### **AWARDS**

### 1st place at YVR's 2023 Hackathon

May 2023

Team 8pes — Crow's Nest

Richmond, BC

• Awarded \$5000 for an AI based project called Crow's Nest that aids YVR Airport with their "NET ZERO 2030" goal.

#### JOB EXPERIENCE

### **Clarius Mobile Health | Full Stack Developer**

May 2022 - January 2023

Python, Django, Docker, PostgreSQL, Fluentd, Nginx, Prometheus, Traefik, Xorg

Burnaby, BC

- Made contributions in a team with GitHub Issues to an enterprise-level cloud platform used by over 50,000 clinicians.
- Refactored 90% of a 7-year-old Python/Django Rest Framework code base, following the we-make-python-styleguide.
- Handled migrations to a PostgreSQL database to correct issues.
- Enabled CI/CD automatic tests on GitHub Actions.
- Improved unit testing coverage significantly using a variety of libraries.
- Added generic form validation to prevent Cross Site Scripting (XSS) exploits.

# Health Gateway Africa Trust | Full Stack Developer

May 2023 - September 2023

TypeScript, React, Fresh, Deno, PostgreSQL, WhatsApp, Google Calendar API

Vancouver, BC

- Worked in a TypeScript, React environment using Deno and Fresh.
- Implemented a WhatsApp chat bot and the Google Calender API into a React web app.
- Organized in a team of 5 using GitHub, Heroku, Trello, and Slack.

### ServTennis | Software Developer

September 2023 - December 2023

Python, PyTorch, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Google Collab, Pandas, NumPy

Vancouver, BC

- Created a multi-faceted PyTorch and TensorFlow machine learning model in a team of 5.
- Learned an extensive topic within a short period through educational material, documentation, and experimentation.

### **NOTEABLE PROJECTS**

AWS TimeSheet Engine | Project Management, RESTful APIs, JavaScript, Cloud Architecture, AWS, Documentation

- Managed a team of 8 developers to create a feature and service rich, serverless, microservice-based, cloud utility.
- Composed cloud infrastructure utilising 15 AWS services including ELB, Step Functions, API Gateway, Lambda, and more.

Lethal Company Quota Optimizer | Python, Flask, JavaScript, React, OOP, Dynamic Programming

• Created a fully hosted React web app with a React front end and Flask back end.

Anon Images | JavaScript, React, Express, CI/CD, Node, Linux, AWS EC2, S3, DynamoDB, Route53, CodePipeline, CodeDeploy

• Created a fully hosted React web app with a React front end, express back end, noSQL database, and AWS services.

Wrath of the Necromancer | Python, Algorithms, Game Design, Documentation, Unit Testing

Created a fully unit-tested, and playable adventure, MUD-like game in Python. Video in portfolio.

PokeAPI Pokedex | Python, RESTful APIs, Design Patterns, OOP, Documentation

- Created an object-oriented, Python program using design patterns including Chain of Responsibility, and factories.
- Utilized a RESTful public API to display relevant information upon requested parameters in a presentable way.

**OpenCV Image Recognition Game Bot** | Python, OpenCV, Self-learning, Machine-learning

• Created a Machine learning program that can automatically play games with appropriate training data. Video in portfolio.

Animal Hustler | Java, JavaFX, FXGL, Documentation, Planning, Object-Oriented Design, Cooperation, UML, Agile

- · Created a fully functional Java game with a partner using object-oriented design principles and Agile development.
- · Conceived and maintained UML diagram prototypes and iterations.

# **EDUCATION**

## **British Columbia Institute of Technology**

September 2021 - December 2023